hey everyone thanks for listening to the
grow your life podcast my name is
jeremiah krakowski and if you haven't
heard of me before i've been building in
the course creation training coaching
niche for over 19 years helping business
owners scale their businesses to eight
figures and i help course creators
coaches trainers and authors get more
customers build their programs create
better programs and make a whole lot of
money doing so with my courses that you
can find over at my website as well as
my one-on-one coaching i also have over
155 episodes of the grow your life
podcast right here which is all about
helping course creators coaches authors
trainers anybody who's building a
business online get more customers we
work on the mindset as well as the
business strategy and those are over 155
episodes totally free for you as well as
thousands of videos on my social media
platforms and youtube on almost every
topic imaginable that you could think of
as a course creator and coach so share
this with somebody if they're thinking
about getting into the industry of
course creation and coaching now today i
want to talk about growing your email
list the email list is one of the most
important assets for a course creator
for a coach for a trainer for a speaker
for an author a teacher an influencer
you have a community of people but it's
an asset that you own
having an email list is an actual asset
in your business your social media
following is not an asset by the way
how do we know this business evaluators
do not evaluate social media as an asset
because it's actually owned by the
social media companies
so a lot of people don't even realize
that is that it could be taken away
tomorrow so there's no worth to
something that can be literally taken
away tomorrow by somebody else
what can't be taken away is names and
email addresses of leads that have
interacted with you and then you build
relationship you know they say your
network is your net worth
your email address is your network in
your business of prospects and customers
and people that want to engage with you
now here's something that i want to say
a lot of people when they grow their
email list they're afraid of people
unsubscribing from them and so one of
the biggest things that stops people
from growing an email list is the lack
of knowledge but also the fear of what
if i use this list wrongly what if i
piss people off what if i upset them
what if i send too many emails and they
don't like me the truth is this the
people that you're meant to work with in
business the people that you are
supposed to be working with they will
stay on your email list
the people who unsubscribe we're not
supposed to be on your email list and
you might say well but those people i
could really impact them i could really
help them
that's not for you to decide
okay so first get that out of your mind
that you're the one that gets to decide
that you get to help somebody just
because you think you can help them
okay i have a lot of people that
unsubscribe from my email list that
for
every reason in the book i think they're
a perfect target customer but they just
for whatever reason can't stand me don't
want to listen to me don't want to hear
anything that i say
so my goal and my focus is i want to
fill my email list with people that are
obsessed with what i do
obsessed with what i teach
they love it they live it they breathe
it and they take action and they build
and they create a business that they can
be proud of something that they can
leave a legacy for their families
something that they can have an impact
on people they can have an impact on
those that they coach and those that
they teach and so because of that you're
not
going to please everybody
one of the biggest things to realize
about email is it's essentially another
social media platform but that's you own
now you might say well i don't own gmail
or i don't know well you don't own that
but you own the names and email
addresses
and so you have ownership of a list of
people
a list of contacts
a list of people that have engaged with
you now here's the thing you don't want
to market to people that have
unsubscribed from you you want to move
them out the door
one of the biggest most important things
that you need to do
is you want people to reject you quick
and to tell you that they have no
interest in what you're doing and it's a
good thing in marketing your delivery
rates will go up your sales will go up
by you segmenting specifically the type
of person that you can most likely help
with your skill set with your talents
with your abilities okay
and so because of that don't be afraid
of people unsubscribing from you now
what are the best ways to grow your
email list well through the internet
it's a it's an internet asset right but
oftentimes we have to
sort of convince people to give us their
information because of some kind of
value exchange
and so we call this an ethical bribe
essentially
and what you're doing is you're bribing
people for their information so you can
join my free
master class that i'm doing that i'm
holding for your email address and
sometimes those aren't valid email
addresses either that's why the email
addresses of purchasers
is the most valuable list that you have
who are the people that have bought your
products and services from you who have
paid you money
who have exchanged currency with you
okay and so you want to kind of have two
buckets you got a bucket of people that
have engaged and bought with you and a
bucket of people that are them and
everybody else so you put the people
that have bought with you into the
bigger bucket and then you have sort of
people that are interested and so your
goal is you're sifting so for the bigger
bucket you want to move as many of them
into being purchasers as you can while
also making sure that as many of them
unsubscribe as possible it's actually
something you want to do
so that your delivery rates are better
so that your language is specifically
honed into the person that you're most
likely that you can help
not everybody
you're not going to help everybody
no matter how nice your heart is on that
it's just not possible it's just not
possible to make everybody like you it's
just not possible to do that and so
segmentation is extremely important when
it comes to marketing or you will be
spending and wasting tons of dollars
trying to make everybody like you
if you have billions of dollars to blow
great do that i know it's people that do
and
they can do that
for the rest of us that are not
billionaires
you probably are very cautious as to how
much you invest your time and your money
and your resources to grow your email
list and so you want to be the most
effective as possible segmentation does
that
we lead with who first and that's what
we talk about your offers my course
irresistible offers that sell
is all about that
we break down the offers that convert to
people
you make an offer to the target customer
of what it is that you do so your course
your book your training program
your seminar your event by the way
events are
they they fall into this category
whatever that is who is the person
who first
who
is the person that you're making an
offer to and what problems do they have
and then you want to basically when you
make an offer sell the vacation
you're not
leading them with the the stuffy hot
boring plane ride to hawaii you want to
sell people on hawaii now when you say
sell an email list you might be confused
you might be like i'm not selling
somebody to give me their email address
you're selling everything in fact
all of us are selling all the time and i
want you to start to change your mindset
about selling
sales doesn't need to be a dirty word
selling is a good thing selling just
means that you presented an offer
and
built up enough trust with another
person so they gave you their money
that's what it is like that's a good
thing right
there's companies out there that i
trust them and i give them my money on a
regular basis that's what selling is
especially when you deliver good
products and services
and so in that
how do you you're selling people on
giving you their email address even for
free offers
even for what's free that's out there
and so it has to be attractive to them
we've ran campaigns with facebook ads
with tick tock ads
to where the offer was a little too
generic cost us 15 bucks
per name and email address that we got
now in some offers that can still be
profitable
for testing
but what i found is that the most
optimized campaigns get under three
dollars a lead and we're hitting two to
three dollars a lead
we know that that's a lane that we can
start to make some profit margins in we
can start to really dive into if you're
getting five times as many leads
for the same amount of investment in
advertising
that's pretty cool because now you have
five more chances
to close a sale
now your goal is going to be you want to
get to a thousand people on your email
list
that's where things really start to take
off for you is when you have a thousand
people on your list you have a thousand
individuals that have given you their
information why does this matter it
gives you enough data to build out more
look-alike audiences for your content
and your products
you're able to figure out by running
surveys and learning what do these
thousand people want from me and
discovering that
and you'll get a great picture as to who
your target customer is and how you can
best serve them now we have a course
called transformational coaching made
simple that walks you through creating
coaching programs that impact people
easy course creation blueprint walks you
through creating online courses that
impact people
you can do this but you have to lead
with
who
first now how do you know what they care
about in those offers or you can test
that out through your social media
content
through the content that you put out
there
you can test out different messages with
different people based off of the
content that you put out into the public
in my course social media content
creation made easy walks you through
creating social media content that is
most likely to get people to engage with
you then you build offers around that so
you build an offer that somebody gives
you their email address for whether it
be a free class
a free event a free webinar a free ebook
something like that that they give you
their email address for and it's related
to
what their desire is what they want from
you
what that person wants from you in
exchange for that email address
now quite simply put we use squarespace
as our website and funnel builder of
course website building made easy walks
you through building squarespace sites
and building out funnels and so we use
this very simply
it takes just seconds to build out
an opt-in form you create a page in
squarespace i'm going to show you how to
do this here in the video
so you create a page in squarespace
here's a page that i created right here
for a free event that i'm hosting march
14th through 16th
all about getting more results out of
your online course or coaching business
okay and so in this people give me their
email address and then that goes on my
email list now we've tested five or six
different offers we were paying more
until we really hit a stride of helping
people that are getting started in their
business what to do what to say how to
say it and setting up their business the
right way to grow their email list run
ads and just eventually make more money
selling courses and coaching and so it's
very easy to create a page like this all
you need is a squarespace account and a
mailchimp account and mailchimp is what
we use for our our email it's owned by
intuit and it's one of the one of the
easiest to use email software's that are
out there so you can sign up you can
actually get a free account and link
this
to squarespace absolutely free up to
2000 email addresses so you can grow
your business for free
using that and then squarespace is about
19 bucks a month so when you create a
page
in squarespace we're just going to
create a blank page right here and i'm
going to show you how easy this is to
build out an offer you know uh for ours
we also used uh canva so you create a
nice little graphic
uh you can find a template in canva for
you know you could use websites right
here
you could edit the text on one of these
templates right here
and then that becomes the image on your
offer okay
and so then right here we go in and we
can
we can add in a you know a headline
some headline text
heading number one
okay center yep
we add our
our image right here under image
and i'll select one that i already have
this one right here
and then we go here and we press
newsletter and the newsletter
is our form and we can type in what this
is
register for this free
event
sign up for this three day intensive
below
totally free
okay and then so then you put storage
you can press other storage options and
then mailchimp zapier also lets you
connect it to other platforms like
clavio and activecampaign and things
like that but mailchimp is a direct
connection right here and so when you
build an email list in mailchimp in your
mailchimp account
you're able to then capture email
addresses
through this form right here on your
website goes to your mailchimp and then
you can email those people
and so now anytime i launch a product
anytime i launch a program anytime i
launch a course people that are on my
email list are buying those from me
and so that's how you can build that as
well and that builds an asset for you
that you can use in your business it's
very easy to build out these offers it's
very easy to build out offers like this
and we walk you through
all of that
in
irresistible offers that sell right here
how to create the perfect offer that
connects with your audience and converts
to sales it's the difference between a
successful business and wishful thinking
because that's the truth without an
offer
nobody wants to buy it and it needs to
grab their attention tell the story of
what they want to happen you're selling
the vacation present it in a way that
makes sense create buy-in
to what you're selling and if it's free
you still got to sell them on giving you
their email address and it leads them to
convert to do what you
desire them to do now not everybody's
going to convert
out of how many people we send to a
landing page to a squeeze page you know
not everybody converts
and and and so don't expect every single
person to sign up with you
you you can start to understand the
psychology behind people based on their
behavior you look at what people they
might say i love your business it's
perfect for me and they never sign up
for anything my friends they're lying to
you it's not real it's not accurate
don't hold that word
don't hold what they said
but an email list shows people that took
action that signed up with you that are
ready to jump in with you and those are
the people that you want to invest in
those are the people that you want to
spend time with and help them grow and
answer their questions and so that's
what i'm here for
jeremiah krakowski that's me i'm here to
help the business owners course creators
and coaches build
launch and scale their profitable course
and coaching business if you're somebody
that wants to do
one-on-one coaching with me we offer
this over at my website right here
you can sign up for
one single payment of five thousand
dollars or six monthly payments of a
thousand dollars to get twelve sessions
of coaching it's a six month coaching
program we meet every two weeks and we
build and work and i come alongside you
to build your business together and so
for those of you that are interested in
that send me a dm send me an email i'd
love to talk with you about 101 coaching
together
all right everybody grow your life share
this podcast with somebody if it has
impacted you if it's helped you if it's
helping you listen through more of the
episodes as well we cover a variety of
topics
and share this with somebody else to
help them grow in their business grow
your life everybody we'll talk soon have
a good one